D. CRISTINA TERRY

Alameda, CA 94501

Phone:415-450-8365| Email: crisdc88@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/dcristinaterry | Github: https://github.com/dcristinaterry

Portfolio: https://dcristinaterry.github.io/portfolio/

Full Stack Engineer

Bilingual (Spanish/English) Full Stack Engineer and passionate problem solver, with 10+ years of experience in multiple roles within the software development field. Enthusiastic and committed to collaborate with others to identify optimum solutions applying best practices. Fulfilled roles within different industries ranging from Systems Analyst to Software Engineer using Java as the main coding language. Recently received in-depth training in Full-Stack Web Development applications from UC Berkeley, learning new technologies such as Tailwinds CSS and React, and languages such as Node, Javascript and MySql. Eager to combine my background in software development and my latest web development skills and utilize my talents to make an immediate contribution as an integral part of your company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java • mySql • React is• Node Js • webServices • JavaScript • HTML • CSS • HandleBars •

Tailwind CSS • Sequelize • Mongo • mongoose • APIs • Es6 • JSON

Applications: Eclipse • VS Code • mySql Workbench • Jira • Zira.

Other: Systems Analysis • Responsive Design • Requirements Gathering and Ambiguity Analysis • Project

Coordination • Test Automation Selenium • Agile Methodology • Object Oriented Programming • Database

Technologies • Web Applications • ETL • TDD

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Study-Buddy | GitHub: https://github.com/crisdc88/P3-Study-Budy Link to Deployed Project: https://ct-study-buddy.herokuapp.com/

Developed an application which provided students with a better means to interact, schedule and host group study sessions.

- Participated with a partner in all phases of the development life cycle, focusing on coding, testing, and debugging.
- Core Responsibilities: System Design, DataBase design, APIs, React js,, component setup and design, Back End Development, Front End Development (React), analyzed the application usability.
- Web Technologies used:: HTML CSS JavaScript Tailwind CSS Axios Moment.js DatePicker Node.js Express MySQL Workbench Sequelize Reactjs JSX Git JSON GitHub Heroku.
- Remote work using Zoom and Slack

Groceries List | GitHub: https://github.com/dcristinaterry/GROCERIES-LIST

Link to Deployed Project: https://ct-groceries-list.herokuapp.com/

Developed an application which allows the user to save a list of items and move them to different places. This allows the user to track the items on every step of the process.

- Solo project; design, develop, debug, and deploy the application
- Core Responsibilities: System Design, DataBase design, Development back and Front End.
- Web Technologies used: HTML CSS JavaScript Bootstrap Node.js Express MySQL Workbench -Git - GitHub - Heroku.

Weather-Info | GitHub: https://github.com/dcristinaterry/WEATHER-INFO Link to Deployed Project: https://dcristinaterry.github.io/WEATHER-INFO/

Developed an application which allows the user to check the weather for a City and have a 5 day weathercast

- Core Responsibilities: System Design, DataBase design, Development back and Front End.
- Web technologies used:: HTML CSS JavaScript Bootstrap jQuery Ajax Git GitHub.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer MicroFocus (Former HPE) *05/*2017 – 02/2020

Pleasanton, CA

Implemented and enhanced enterprise software solutions to transform, enrich and migrate large structured datasets.

- Migrated social media data of financial organizations into the Digital Safe Cloud system using Java, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, RESTful web services, Bash, MySQL and SMAP frameworks. This resulted in over \$10,000 to \$100.000 USD per migration in revenue to the company, creating a new revenue stream.
- Migrated PST data into the Digital Safe Cloud system using Visual Studio .net, JPA, Hibernate, RESTful web services, Bash, MySQL and SMAP frameworks.
- Collaborated with project managers, client directors and team members from project inception to completion, providing technical expertise and troubleshooting as required.

SVC-ITO Service Delivery MicroFocus (Former HPE)

*09/*2014 – 05/2017

Pleasanton, CA

Analyzed and Implemented an Automation Testing Framework iSTF to build Automated test cases for MicroFocus' applications (Digital Safe and Supervisor) based on client requirements.

- Decreased over 60% monitoring time, generation of early alerts and reduced need for manual systems checks for all clients, including but not limited to major organizations such as TD bank, North Western Mutual and Shell.
- Configured the application to meet client requirements.
- QA; Testing and troubleshooting, debugging errors and maintaining direct communication with the clients.
- Influenced the decision making of choosing new technologies, architecture and programming languages.

Systems Analyst / Product Manager. Bancolombia

02/2009 - 02/2013

Medellin, Colombia

Contributed to the development of credit card application solutions with a major focus on integration with legacy software.

- Successfully led the design and development acting as the key expert on the new credit card reward system and compliance report application.
- Redesigned internal processes using various technologies including SAP, Sales Force and others.
- Oversaw progress, gathered requirements, created technical designs and other deliverables in alignment with functional requirements for various projects.
- Handled IT support training on all new applications.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate (2020): Berkeley University Extension, Berkeley, CA A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Master of Science in Computer Science: MIU - Fairfield, Iowa

Bachelor of Science in Systems Engineering: EAFIT University - Medellin, Colombia

Professional Development: ITIL v3 Foundation Certification